to approach this is to look from the
point of view of blind blind signatures
right I guess blind signatures are
mostly familiar to this audience right
yes more should be should be familiar
far be wasabi user where every was a
beeper user I guess so the idea of
credentials is similar in the sense that
you get some blinded token that was
signed by some server and the server
does not see the message that was being
signed now the additional idea to a
credential is that it's not only a
message that it's being signed but
instead it's multiple attributes that
can be signed and these attributes can
be anything and now the interesting
thing is that you can selectively reveal
these attributes you can say here I have
a token and in this token there I have
there is this attribute and it has this
value so the NOC standard example is you
haven't token from your government let's
say and it says your age basically your
or say that st. birthdate is is one of
attributes and then is signed now what
you can do with that you can only show
your attribute you can also show that
it's in a certain range you can do a
range proof so what you would do is if
you go to the cinema you don't have to
reveal your age you don't have to reveal
anything else that is included in your
credential you only have to show that
you are older than 18 years and that
works with such a credential and these
attributes are pretty flexible you can
for example besides range proof system
you can show that if you have two blind
tokens
attributes are the same for example yeah
so mathematically I think the best way
to think about this is as Peterson multi
commitments so in normal Peterson
commitments right you have some
randomness and you use that to commit to
a value and you basically have two
different generators group generators
now with these multi commitments used in
some of these credential approaches you
have randomness and now you commit to
multiple attributes and only a single
one and usually you have as many
generators as they have attributes so I
think historically one of the first
notions of these credentials was by
brands
I think Peter price not quite sure he
has he wrote his pH pH TV yeah
okay um Francis's last name and he wrote
a PhD thesis about his idea of doing
credentials and it's actually quite
interesting I can recommend it it's um
not too technical and he has a lot more
ideas than just credentials and but one
problem with it was that so far every
attempt at proving its secure in the
random Oracle model failed and this is
where this anonymous credentials light
paper comes in because they have a
construction that is provably secure and
it you can do basically the same things
or very similar things as with
credentials there might be one minor
problem this one last time I looked at
it I did not really solve because in the
paper they say for 128-bit security we
recommend using a group of 576 bits and
of course our sakti group is only 256
bits so it's not sure if you can use
that it's often the case that due to the
proof these groups need to be much
larger than they are used in practice
even for snort signatures our website or
our secti group would actually be too
small for 128-bit security mostly people
say yeah let's just an artifact of the
proof it doesn't really matter that much
but in order to verify that we need we
would need to look into the proof more
closely yeah thank you
yeah that's almost everything I wanted
to say like the other thing I wanted to
say is that these tokens are pretty
flexible compared to just more
signatures so at the building of Bitcoin
conference 2018 I talked about how to
use this to basically swap a token that
is in or that it was created with an
anonymous credential with an untrained
or off trained bit cone on lightning
without the server knowing that this
happened and without having to trust the
other party yeah thank you I'd like to
point out so we are reviewing right now
a paper called anonymous credentials
light and as Jonas pointed out this is
an improvement on the brand's
credentials in fact it has it has one
difference between the brand Bank
credentials well where this is
more secure of course because the brands
contentious couldn't be proven but
actually these tokens are unlink yes on
linkable with each other so if you have
a credential you can create as many
blind signatures for it and you can
prove that credential as many times as
you want
unlike the brand credentials because
there they are linker bus
so you can only use up to as much
signatures as much the the the the
designer allows you in in our case would
be the coordinator so that's actually
something that we would desire if we
would want to build on top of this
anyway if I may add to that I would say
that brands credentials are also unlink
able and if you can talk to the server
right because that's what you also
usually do any cash you basically show
the serial number of your old token you
create a new token you show that the
tokens are the same in zero knowledge
and then you get a signature on the new
token and that way you get an unlikeable
token I think the advanced anonymous
credential slide is that you can do that
without having to talk to the server yes
it's called I think rash once or that's
what usually comes up anyway so a bit
bit more there because the same out or
they're working on this this for are for
probably a decade after this paper and
and they actually came up with something
called mercury are signatures where they
don't need so much crypto as much as in
this paper but but in a very
straightforward way they could achieve
the exact same thing with with these
mercurial signatures and even more
they were working on something called
delegate Abel anonymous credentials and
there are the three keys that you could
actually delegate the ownership of the
credential to someone else so in our
case that would be I think giving money
to someone and I wouldn't be able to
redeem it but you would which is
actually pretty nice oh my god I wasn't
talking last thing you said was in our
case that would be yeah it's it's
interesting because I think it's
recording everything what I'm saying but
you didn't hear so I think what the
studies in our case it would be that we
could give the we could give well pay
someone in a coin jury round without us
being able to redeem it but that someone
would be able to redeem it as an output
of the coin join so so I just wanted to
point out that del tours were actually
working on this this line of research
for a long time and they think they came
up with much better constructions and
easier ones too so if someone would like
to look into these anonymous credentials
and definitely look into the newer stuff
there okay so far any comment here
because I want to approach it also from
coin joining point of view that why did
we why did we wanted to use it and why
we don't want to use it anymore so in
the the problem that we are trying to
solve is
be able to to to have some kind of dizzy
divisible ecash system actually that
that allows us to come with any input in
in a tour ident in unanimity network
identity and then we we get back some
some credit for for for that input and
and if we come with another input later
then we get back some credit and then
somehow we can combine those credits and
came with only one output or we could
also break those credits down and with a
with a stupid blind signature scheme we
would have to create a bunch of
denominations and a bunch of signatures
so why this paper would be handy here
because we still need to create the
bunch of denominations but we wouldn't
need to create a bunch of signatures the
user could create the signatures the
blind signatures for their credentials
later however we actually came up with
with the solution based on homomorphic
cryptographic commitments range proofs
and blind signature scheme that that
that works with the Sohma morphic
cryptographic commitments in a way that
we can actually come with an anonymity
Network Identity register input get back
something come with another anonymity
network identity register another input
get back something and we could combine
that to something in zero knowledge that
in a way that we could prove this error
that we could make any kind of outputs
out of those and we could have done it
with this
credentials in some way or form but we
would still had to have denominations in
order to to achieve some kind of privacy
that that was the the thought of blind
right so I understand instead of
registering all inputs at once you would
be able to registering them with
different identities right yes we can
come with different identities with any
any number of inputs and with we can
come with different identities to to
register any output that's but so so you
would provide a let's say one Bitcoin
input and another one Bitcoin input
later and then you would get to one
input one Bitcoin tokens and that could
be used to add a to Bitcoin output or
something like that and you don't have
to show that your inputs where one
Bitcoin you just show that the sum is
equal to two bitcoins yes in fact even
more we can merge them and break them
down in any way your shape or form I'm
not sure okay
IV a risk because this this session is
about anonymous credentials and I will
bring up some topics but yeah I will a
risk risk it to explain playing it to
you because it's it's really interesting
I think it's really no no but you can
think about it the breaking part is easy
and and I think that that you understand
it easily and I can explain it to you
because if you have one Bitcoin and you
want to pay zero point one Bitcoin to
someone then it would be like this you
create
- feathers and let's say feathers and
commitments 20.1 Bitcoin and 20.9
Bitcoin those will be your outputs in
the coin join right so far it's clear so
and then you register that two patters
and commitment and Patterson commitment
for four for your one Bitcoin input and
you of course tell the coordinator that
hey this one Bitcoin input I'm going to
prove that it is mine and this is the
sum of my feathers and commitments by
the way we create more feathers and
commitments with with zeros but but it
doesn't matter for for now make sense
and then we also found the blind
signature scheme that works with
feathers and commitments so the
coordinator can give us something from
what we can create a signature on our
values which is cool because then we can
just come at output registration that
hey I'm registering this zero point one
Bitcoin output and I have a signature on
it and with another anonymity network
identity hey I'm registering this zero
point nine Bitcoin output and I have a
signature on it so this is the breaking
part and the merging part is is
different because we couldn't figure out
with the with patters and commitments
range proofs and yeah of course that
there needs to be range proof along with
the patters and commitments but III
think that's obvious anyway we couldn't
figure it out we
with blind signature scheme on Paterson
commitment but we actually had to use
BLS signatures and with that we could
figure out how to how to merge together
more than one commitment yeah so it's
pretty cool yeah
any question on that or we can get back
to this paper yeah I don't quite
understand why that wouldn't work if you
if you not say have a point one and a
point nine talk bit Co and talking right
yes don't you just have to show to the
server that both tokens some up or or
maybe even better
you create a new token with a one
Bitcoin value you don't show the server
your or the value of the new token and
but you show the server that the some of
the old tokens is the value of the new
token wouldn't that work for your dream
your first suggestion yes that works it
just there is some probably negligible
privacy loss right like you you tell you
expose the server that you have a zero
point one between and a 0.9 Bitcoin
feathers and commitments and the self I
don't think at least with anonymous
credential slide I don't think you have
to do that necessarily I think you can
show that the sum is the value of your
new token and you don't have to show
anything more to the server I think with
your first suggestion I was talking
about that right okay that that's not a
huge privacy thing so it can work but we
figured out how to do it even without
that so your second suggestion could you
repeat it maybe a match
I thought I was only making one
suggestion here so perhaps that was that
I'm not sure what the second one would
be so your first suggestion was to take
two blind signature of 0.1 and 0.9 and
register them together to the server to
the coordinator is that correct perhaps
I wouldn't call this registering I would
just call this like perhaps like just a
reissuance we've used that term before
you have a token and you just want to
get a new one with a new serial number
and these tokens are on linkable and the
same would work if you show two tokens
and the new token where the new token is
the sum of the former tokens and you
don't have to show the actual values to
the server you just have to show that
the sum matches to the new value and
then we wouldn't have that privacy laws
of having to show the individual values
of the old tokens yes so the thing is we
get this signature the blind signature
on the data itself which means if we
want a reissuance face there then we
would have to expose the D values okay
so there might be some some scheme that
works with that well we'd be Ellis
signature we actually figured it out how
to do that because they're the
signatures actually has the message
itself so it's really fresh I just
learned about it today
and-and-and-and something like that that
you can give the two two blind that'd be
a signature too
the coordinator and proved that their
sum is dis value and because of the
blind BLS signatures are the the unique
tokens there this way we won't have
problems so with anonymous credentials I
think you would have to you would have
to to create a bunch of bunch of
denominations all right I don't think so
I think this is exactly the magic of
these anonymous credentials that you can
do these some proofs similar to what you
just described with their BLS signatures
okay I okay that's yeah what we came up
with indeed but I'm not sure in this
paper yeah I remember correctly perhaps
they're not showing this in this paper
but this is something that is like a
central concept in the bronze PhD thesis
and I believe you can do the same thing
with anonymous credentials because both
types of credentials look actually very
similar all right I'm not sure if it
would it make sense to start
investigating this instead of doing it
with BLS signatures actually I think I
don't know I would do whatever is
easiest actually because I guess for
your application or in general does
make too big of a difference if you use
be late I mean if you think that parents
are secure and BLS signatures are secure
and this whole bunch of crypto sanctions
and I think you can just use that if
that's easier
I don't think you have to restrict
yourself to something that is that works
in the discrete logarithm paradigm the
discrete logarithm program you know they
use parents so it's different different
curves and different cryptic assumptions
okay
all right so yeah I I'm not sure it is
easier for us because the implementation
since ours I think still looking behind
of the BLS signature implementations so
on the other hand it's it's such a
simple scheme that even they could
explain they could even explain it to me
who doesn't understand crypto that much
so okay the BLS doesn't have
implementation and if so how is it count
so I can find it I think it does not
have implementation in c-sharp
it has for a couple of languages I think
the main implementation C++ and there is
bindings for that okay I think there's
an implementation of brands credentials
in c-sharp right let's see you prove
library okay yes I was playing around
with that in fact I ported it to dotnet
core and it's not that obvious how to
use that but the code is very very clean
and very nice so I would have loved to
go with you proof what's the problem
with you
that doesn't solve our problem as far as
I understand it you see I need a bunch
of stuff to do with that also people are
talking about that it's not very secure
and things like that no one's found in a
vulnerability yet
brands credentials own as far as I know
[Music]
no it's a difficult question but I think
the the some proof that I mentioned
earlier should work just as well with
brands credentials you don't need
multiple determining denominations
because brands credentials would be able
to prove the sound and does it have the
how good range proofs applied to that
yeah you probably still have to do this
range proofs to show that the values
don't overflow but I I'm not sure the
you proof library does that already for
you and it really looked into the
library never and what is there is how
about the merging of the coins I think
that could be a problem there that you
cannot merge two attributes together in
a way that it both prevents the bus
spending and and you don't expose the
attribute you know the values only the
some of them I'm not sure that that's
possible I think it is I think that's
the point of branch credential if you do
a reassurance you don't have to show all
the attributes
you just assure the server you prove to
the server that your new token doesn't
have any other value than the sum of
your old tokens combined I think and
this is possible with brands credentials
you don't need their age when is there
yeah you would need the reasons okay so
now finally there is an argument why our
scheme is better because we don't need
race okay but for unknown credentials
light but okay so that sounds like
something that BLS or parents could do
like merging different credentials
together without communication with the
server so nice to me that sounds
plausible yeah actually I'm just going
to read a few things about here is that
you prove about you prove from the the
article that to be for everyone knows
what we are talking about from the
efficiency point of view
therefore the you prove credential
system based on brands work
acquired and implemented by Microsoft
CMAs attractive you prove does not allow
on linkable use of credentials in order
to unlink ability use a credential again
in order to unlink ibly use a credential
again a user must get it reissued which
while which which actually suggests that
in fact that this paper doesn't have
linkable credentials only on on linkable
on these lines don't suggest that but
that's what's in the paper
let me see one more ting there when such
a proof is carried out it cannot be
linked to previous uses of the same
credential or any other identifying
information about the user oh yes this
is this is what I what I'm talking about
here we actually want the opposite in
order to avoid the bus spending we want
to use we want a used to be linked to
previous uses of the same credential
which brands provide and this scheme
does not I'm not sure how hard would it
be to to implement it would it be only a
simplification or this would be a major
headache to implement linkable
credentials on top of on top of Asia
construct and what construct is this
paper anonymous credentials light is
real
yeah I think that's easy because one of
the attributes would just be the serial
number that the server stores I mean the
service tones the serial numbers of
course that have been used right so okay
then woody I guess yeah you wouldn't
need the Rishi once again right you
don't show your serial number and then
you get a new token you know if you if
you put a serial number into the the
attribute yes you cannot prove that scum
I mean the serial number is there you
know so what you do is you show your old
credentials can be multiple you show
the serial numbers for each of those
credentials you proof that the serial
numbers are actually the ones contained
in your credentials the server checks
that these serial numbers have not been
used you show the new token that you
created with a fresh serial number
serial number that you chose randomly
and then you do the some proof and that
way you don't have to show anything to
the server but the serial numbers we
would we would create blind signatures
to as many I don't know
yeah the problem is with blind citizens
red is blind signatures are unstructured
you just have this message and then you
can put different things into the
message but then you cannot efficiently
prove anything about these individual
attributes in your message and this is
why these credential schemes are
superior to the normal blind signatures
yeah all right
so there may be something here yeah I'd
also like to look into this
pls stuff definitely that seems
interesting going to link the repository
in the in the comment here but don't
don't share it yet because we did not
figure out the name and we have a stupid
name for for now okay yes yeah
do you guys have anything to to ask odd
talk about regarding regarding anything
maybe everyone is minute go ahead Lucas
no I have no now question because I I'm
not I don't know these primitives yet so
I have to study a bit more yeah I
learned most of that from so Adam Beck
he once gave a presentation about brands
credentials at block stream so I learned
a lot from him but wasn't public
unfortunately I think I have the slides
but I don't think they're very helpful
so perhaps the best starting point is
still brands pitch these theses it's
very long but some just have to check
out some parts of it I think because
because especially the things like this
anonymous credential slide there seems
to be like the difficult thing about or
to grasp about it is not I mean this
scheme exists but the question is how do
you use it and how do you use it with
serial numbers and to get ecash tokens
with multiple determinations right
that's not in the anonymous credentials
light paper that's something that brands
talks a little bit more about as we as
we reviewed this paper and we looked
into that well how could we use it for
ets kind of stuff then we just stumbled
upon a tremendous amount of literature
there that how to do divisible in cash
systems and three like
a couple of hundred of paper is is is
going on on this issue but the thing is
they are solving things that we don't
need to solve because Co injuries are
inherently secure if someone doesn't see
their outputs then it it's not going to
sign and that here so our job is
basically to simplify what they have
right there's also the concept of
optimal ecash which also doesn't seem to
be very practical in the Bitcoin world
because in offline cash if you double
spend you reveal your secret key which
perhaps as if you're an attacker that's
not a big problem to you because you
already have your Bitcoin so you don't
care about the secret keys in your token
you have twice as many Bitcoin and says
you would have normally so they don't
seem to apply because everyone is online
in fact even where the participants are
online although you're not
yeah this this idea of merging inputs
and and so on that's really interesting
I think yeah we are going to work on
that and either look into that issue
that's where we figured out how things
should be but we are going to to create
a draft and and send it to the Bitcoin
dev mailing list and and and things like
that and also for the next was a B
research Club each train is going to
actually is going to write down exactly
this scheme the cryptography part of it
and and that's what I would like to
propose for the next four so we research
club because as we looked through e-cash
papers and anonymous credential papers
and every kind of papers it looks like
this is the simplest and
most straightforward solution for four
really arbitrary Cohen joins which we
are not going to do but we would like to
have that that flexibility and and
that's what lets us improve upon it in
the future max asked what about server
decided equal value outputs anyone
understands the question all right sorry
max we can't reply you okay oh yeah one
more interesting thing here max figured
out that for tiny one of the author of
this paper we are talking about it was
actually had some involvement in town
babbitt not sure exactly what but but
yes she was she was doing something
tomba bit okay and I think if no one
would like to say anything because this
was quite a difficult paper then we can
we can cut this short
unlike other other conversations and we
can we can go so so do you guys have
anything as you would like to talk about
not yet ready I mean I'm just fascinated
about things that you guys talk about
yeah I think I talked about almost
everything I know about it so let me
know how this progresses and what you
find out yeah definitely we are going to
talk about our scheme and the next was
Severus
Club if no one has an objection or
alternatively we could review Adam gives
on from zero knowledge to bulletproof
paper I think that could be could be
useful or or our scheme which might be
more might make more sense to be honest
but it could change maybe we figure out
how there is something utterly wrong
with this and and the next week would be
would be pointless but I doubt at this
point we really reviewed a lot of things
last week so should the next generation
wasabi mixing technology be the topic of
the rest that's a very surgical what do
you guys think yeah I think it's good
but there was a question from Max and
that is there a difference of users who
want to be a part of the equal value
denomination and those who want only
specific amounts yeah no there is no
difference it's equal value
denominations as I imagine it right now
although we did not work this out at all
but I think that could be something that
the users create by themselves so if I
participate in a mix then I'm going to
parties I'm going to ask for outputs off
of some standard denominations that I I
guess I estimate other users I suspect
other users are going to do too so that
that that that would be but I could
create outputs in any way shape or form
up to the maximum limits of course as I
as I would like to even do a paid to end
point transaction in a coin joint which
would be neat yeah it sounds good also a
really interesting thing we just had a
talk with Taj Taj not gonna pronounce it
so one of the guy who who who came up
with the Lightning Network and he
actually came up with the coins for
protocol there is still some denial of
service issues he didn't figure out but
he came up with the coins for protocol
that of their top route ease in snorunt
approaches in Bitcoin and we he could do
coin swabs those could be completely
unnoticeable and that's that's a really
exciting so I just wanted to share this
this fresh information okay
all right thank you guys and sorry for
this unconventional wasabi research club
now usually Aviv does a very good good
job at explaining the concept at the
beginning but he he couldn't make it
last minute so no one could really
prefer but Nick gave a great summary of
the paper so absolutely I mean you guys
did a good job and thanks for that yes
things thank you Nick and thank you for
watching this special one all right then
I guess that's it
like share and subscribe bye bye bye